Register of the Flora Belle Jan letters
Hoover Institution Archives
Flora Belle Jan letters
1918-1949
2011C26
Jan, Flora Belle, 1906-1950
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Contains Flora Belle Jan's letters to her friend Ludmelia Holstein, relating to journalism in the United States and China and to personal matters. Published as Unbound Spirit: Letters of Flora Belle Jan (Urbana, 2009).
Administrative Information
Access
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Flora Belle Jan, a Chinese American journalist, was born in the United States in 1906 to immigrant parents. She studied literature at University of California, Berkeley, and the University of Chicago. Jan worked as a journalist in both the United States and China for The Fresno Herald, The San Francisco Examiner, The Chinese Students' Monthly, The Peking Chronicle, and other periodicals. Her writings reflect the encounters and reflections of a Chinese American woman in an era of race and gender limitations.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of letters by Flora Belle Jan written over a thirty-year period, recording her personal struggles in an environment of political turmoil in the 1930s and 1940s, offering unique insight into the social and political situation of an educated, middle-class, professional Chinese American woman.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Journalism--United States.; Journalism--China.; Chinese American women.; Journalists.; Holstein, Ludmelia, 1905-1976.
Collection Contents
- United States, 1918-1932 (Box 1)
  - California, 1918-1925 (Folder 1)
    - 1918 (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1919 (Folder 1: 2)
    - 1920 (Folder 1: 3)
    - 1921 (Folder 1: 4)
    - 1922 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1923 (Folder 1: 6)
    - 1924 (Folder 1: 7)
    - 1925 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Chicago, 1926-1932 (Folder 1)
    - 1926 (Folder 1: 9)
    - 1927 (Folder 1: 10)
    - 1928 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 1929 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1930 (Folder 1: 13)
    - 1931 (Folder 2: 1)
    - 1932 (Folder 2: 2)
- China, 1932-1949 (Folder 2)
  - Kaifeng, 1932-1933 (Folder 2)
    - 1932 (Folder 2: 3)
    - 1933 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Peiping (Beijing), 1934-1941 (Folder 2)
    - 1934 (Folder 2: 5)
    - 1935 (Folder 2: 6)
    - 1936 (Folder 2: 7)
    - 1937 (Folder 2: 8)
    - 1938 (Folder 2: 9)
    - 1939 (Folder 2: 10)
    - 1940 (Folder 2: 11)
    - 1941 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Chungking (Chongqing), 1944-1945 (Folder 2)
    - 1944 (Folder 2: 13)
    - 1945 (Folder 2: 14)
    - 1946 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Shanghai, 1947-1949 (Folder 2)
    - 1947 (Folder 2: 16)
    - 1948 (Folder 2: 17)
    - 1949 (Folder 2: 18)